const MIS = [
  {
    question: "Which of the following best defines End-User Computing (EUC)?",
    options: [
      "A programming language used exclusively by non-programmers to develop applications.",
      "The process of outsourcing software development to end-users.",
      "Platforms and tools designed for non-programmers to create applications and outputs.",
      "Advanced computing systems accessible only to experienced programmers."
    ],
    answer: "Platforms and tools designed for non-programmers to create applications and outputs."
  },
  {
    question: "Which type of End-User Computing (EUC) prioritizes mobility and connectivity regardless of platform, commonly offered as a service rather than a standalone application?",
    options: [
      "Desktop and Laptop Computers",
      "Desktop Operating Systems and Applications",
      "Smartphones and Wearables",
      "Mobile, Web, and Cloud Applications"
    ],
    answer: "Mobile, Web, and Cloud Applications"
  },
  {
    question: "Which type of End-User Computing (EUC) primarily focuses on mobile hardware platforms (such as smartphones, tablets, and smartwatches) and the software they can use (such as apps and widgets)?",
    options: [
      "Desktop and Laptop Computers",
      "Desktop Operating Systems and Applications",
      "Smartphones and Wearables",
      "Mobile, Web, and Cloud Applications"
    ],
    answer: "Smartphones and Wearables"
  },
  {
    question: "Which type of End-User Computing (EUC) involves the most common hardware aspect of an EUC solution, namely computers. These can be customized for any specification of an end-user.",
    options: [
      "Desktop and Laptop Computers",
      "Desktop Operating Systems and Applications",
      "Smartphones and Wearables",
      "Mobile, Web, and Cloud Applications"
    ],
    answer: "Desktop and Laptop Computers"
  },
  {
    question: "Which type of End-User Computing (EUC) covers the software aspect of desktop and laptop computers; they can either come packaged with an operating system (OS) or sold/developed separately?",
    options: [
      "Desktop and Laptop Computers",
      "Desktop Operating Systems and Applications",
      "Virtual Desktops and Application",
      "Mobile, Web, and Cloud Applications"
    ],
    answer: "Desktop Operating Systems and Applications"
  },
  {
    question: "Which type of End-User Computing (EUC) further enhances mobility and connectivity through the development of online, cloud-based computing solutions commonly offered 'as-a-service'?",
    options: [
      "Desktop and Laptop Computers",
      "Desktop Operating Systems and Applications",
      "Virtual Desktops and Application",
      "Mobile, Web, and Cloud Applications"
    ],
    answer: "Virtual Desktops and Applications"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following best defines End-User Development (EUD)?",
    options: [
      "A programming language exclusively for professional developers.",
      "A practice in which end-users develop their information systems with the aid of IT professionals.",
      "A system where end-users are entirely excluded from the development process.",
      "A process where IT professionals develop information systems without any input from end-users."
    ],
    answer: "A practice in which end-users develop their information systems with the aid of IT professionals."
  },
  {
    question: "What is one benefit of end-user computing mentioned in the passage?",
    options: [
      "Empowerment of end-users",
      "Dependence on DP professionals",
      "Decreased productivity of professional workers",
      "Increase in unnecessary business process steps"
    ],
    answer: "Empowerment of end-users"
  },
  {
    question: "How does end-user computing help in reducing unnecessary steps in business processes?",
    options: [
      "By limiting the involvement of end-users",
      "By eliminating the need for DP professionals",
      "By empowering end-users to revise or eliminate steps",
      "By increasing steps in the processes"
    ],
    answer: "By empowering end-users to revise or eliminate steps"
  },
  {
    question: "Why is the empowerment of end-users considered a benefit of end-user computing?",
    options: [
      "It provides members with skills to create viable systems solutions",
      "It decreases productivity in white-collar workers",
      "It prevents end-users from developing any information systems",
      "It complicates the process of creating viable systems solutions"
    ],
    answer: "It provides members with skills to create viable systems solutions"
  },
  {
    question: "What problem can be minimized by involving end-users in the development of information system solutions?",
    options: [
      "Implementation problems for applications",
      "Lack of user-friendly systems",
      "Increase in unnecessary business process steps",
      "Shortage of DP professionals"
    ],
    answer: "Implementation problems for applications"
  },
  {
    question: "How does end-user computing help in providing user-friendly systems?",
    options: [
      "By transferring the implementation process to DP professionals",
      "By making the systems complex and difficult to understand",
      "By limiting the involvement of end-users",
      "By empowering end-users to create simple solutions"
    ],
    answer: "By empowering end-users to create simple solutions"
  },
  {
    question: "What is a common consequence of errors in analysis in End-User Computing?",
    options: [
      "Improved software quality",
      "Increased efficiency",
      "Questionable software quality",
      "Enhanced documentation"
    ],
    answer: "Questionable software quality"
  },
  {
    question: "What is a typical challenge associated with documentation in End-User Computing?",
    options: [
      "Abundance of documentation",
      "Adequate formal training",
      "Lack of documentation",
      "Easy maintenance process"
    ],
    answer: "Lack of documentation"
  },
  {
    question: "What is a potential issue related to corporate models in Decision Support Systems developed by end-users?",
    options: [
      "High accuracy rates",
      "Low reliance on spreadsheets",
      "Faulty models",
      "Reduced strategic decision-making"
    ],
    answer: "Faulty models"
  },
  {
    question: "What security concern may arise due to the nature of end-user developed software?",
    options: [
      "Implementation of robust security measures",
      "Enhanced data protection",
      "Reduced risk of manipulation",
      "Possible security/piracy issue"
    ],
    answer: "Possible security/piracy issue"
  },
  {
    question: "What percentage of spreadsheets used in Decision Support Systems may contain errors according to recent research?",
    options: [
      "10%",
      "25%",
      "38%",
      "50%"
    ],
    answer: "38%"
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is an example of an Application Package in end-user computing tools?",
    options: [
      "Java programming language",
      "Microsoft Office Suite",
      "HTML",
      "C++ programming language"
    ],
    answer: "Microsoft Office Suite"
  },
  {
    question: "Which category of end-user computing tools allows users to develop their computing solutions and consolidate them to form small information systems?",
    options: [
      "Third-Generation Programming Languages",
      "Integrated Development Environments",
      "Fourth-Generation Programming Languages",
      "Application Packages"
    ],
    answer: "Fourth-Generation Programming Languages"
  },
  {
    question: "Which category of end-user computing tools are pre-written software packages that are marketed commercially. They support standard business functions such as payroll, ledgers, scheduling, inventory control, etc.?",
    options: [
      "Third-Generation Programming Languages",
      "Integrated Development Environments",
      "Fourth-Generation Programming Languages",
      "Application Packages"
    ],
    answer: "Application Packages"
  },
  {
    question: "Which tool includes diary management, electronic notebooks, directories, project management tools, personal digital assistants, Bluetooth?",
    options: [
      "Data Handling Tools",
      "Office Automation Tools",
      "Graphic Design",
      "Knowledge Management"
    ],
    answer: "Office Automation Tools"
  },
  {
    question: "Which tool includes graphic software, computer-aided design?",
    options: [
      "Data Handling Tools",
      "Office Automation Tools",
      "Graphic Design",
      "Knowledge Management"
    ],
    answer: "Graphic Design"
  },
  {
    question: "Which tool includes expert systems, data mining, information retrieval?",
    options: [
      "Data Handling Tools",
      "Office Automation Tools",
      "Graphic Design",
      "Knowledge Management"
    ],
    answer: "Knowledge Management"
  },
  {
    question: "Which tool includes word processing, desktop publishing, web-publishing, presentation software, document management systems, work-flow management systems?",
    options: [
      "Text and Multimedia Handling Tools",
      "Office Automation Tools",
      "Communication Tools",
      "Group Systems / Computer Supported Collaborative Work"
    ],
    answer: "Text and Multimedia Handling Tools"
  },
  {
    question: "Which tool includes e-mail, voice over IP (VoIP), fax, WAP, pagers?",
    options: [
      "Text and Multimedia Handling Tools",
      "Office Automation Tools",
      "Communication Tools",
      "Group Systems / Computer Supported Collaborative Work"
    ],
    answer: "Communication Tools"
  },
  {
    question: "Which tool includes teleconferencing, virtual workspaces/desktops?",
    options: [
      "Text and Multimedia Handling Tools",
      "Office Automation Tools",
      "Communication Tools",
      "Group Systems / Computer Supported Collaborative Work"
    ],
    answer: "Group Systems / Computer Supported Collaborative Work"
  },
  {
    question: "What is one of the primary goals of office automation?",
    options: [
      "To increase manual paperwork within departments",
      "To integrate basic office requirements for efficient operation",
      "To encourage separate handling of office functions",
      "To require additional workforce and resources for office tasks"
    ],
    answer: "To integrate basic office requirements for efficient operation"
  },
  {
    question: "What is the primary function of an Office Information System (OIS)?",
    options: [
      "To hinder workflow and communication among office workers",
      "To decrease efficiency in managing office activities",
      "To improve workflow and communication of office workers",
      "To limit the use of software, hardware, and networking in office environments"
    ],
    answer: "To improve workflow and communication of office workers"
  },
  {
    question: "These are operations or actions that can be performed by activating a function key or a key sequence on a workstation.",
    options: [
      "Functions ",
      "Software Packages",
      "Process Software",
      "Word Processing"
    ],
    answer: "Functions "
  },
  {
    question: "These are bundled applications that interact with a system's resources to perform tasks, such as document production, spreadsheet creation, and information presentation?",
    options: [
      "Functions",
      "Software Packages ", 
      "Process Software",
      "Word Processing"
    ],
    answer: "Software Packages "
  },
  {
    question: "These are software, either individual or bundled, that provide specific capabilities other than those commonly offered.",
    options: [
      "Functions",
      "Software Packages",
      "Process Software ",
      "Word Processing"
    ],
    answer: "Process Software "
  },
  {
    question: "This type of software is designed for developing textual documents; it permits users to create, format, modify, and print documents electronically.",
    options: [
      "Functions",
      "Software Packages",
      "Process Software",
      "Word Processing "
    ],
    answer: "Word Processing "
  },
  {
    question: "This type of software is used extensively for accounting and financial purposes, and is designed for maintaining, manipulating, and calculating numerical data.",
    options: [
      "Electronic Spreadsheet ",
      "Database Management",
      "Desktop Publishing",
      "Graphics Design"
    ],
    answer: "Electronic Spreadsheet "
  },
  {
    question: "A software for organized electronic storage, allowing users to arrange, print, search, and display information efficiently.",
    options: [
      "Electronic Spreadsheet",
      "Database Management",
      "Desktop Publishing ",
      "Graphics Design"
    ],
    answer: "Database Management"
  },
  {
    question: "Software lays out text, graphics, and pictures on a page, enabling tasks like integrating text and graphics, adjusting sizes, and using various type styles. As word processing software advances, the line between the two is blurring.",
    options: [
      "Electronic Spreadsheet",
      "Database Management",
      "Desktop Publishing",
      "Graphics Design"
    ],
    answer: "Desktop Publishing"
  },
  {
    question: "Software creates charts and graphs from spreadsheet data or user input. It offers versatility in presentation formats like bar, line, or pie charts. Users can also add pictures and symbols. Examples include Microsoft PowerPoint for presentations and Adobe Photoshop for graphic design.",
    options: [
      "Electronic Spreadsheet",
      "Database Management",
      "Desktop Publishing",
      "Graphics Design "
    ],
    answer: "Graphics Design "
  },
  {
    question: "Software helps users identify tasks, resources, and time requirements for projects, plan and track progress, and generate varied reports. It automatically adjusts project details based on user input, ensuring accurate scheduling.",
    options: [
      "Project Management",
      "Calendar",
      "Electronic Communication",
      "None"
    ],
    answer: "Project Management"
  },
  {
    question: "Software schedules events across multiple calendars, with added features like 'to do' lists, reminders, and time tracking. As it integrates across platforms, it's becoming a staple in office automation, albeit considered a minor aspect.",
    options: [
      "Project Management",
      "Calendar",
      "Electronic Communication",
      "None"
    ],
    answer: "Calendar"
  },
  {
    question: "This type of software permits sending information to users through their computers communication links.",
    options: [
      "Project Management",
      "Calendar",
      "Electronic Communication",
      "None"
    ],
    answer: "Electronic Communication"
  },
  {
    question: "EUD stands for:",
    options: [
      "End-User Development",
      "End-User Deployment",
      "End-User Documentation",
      "End-User Design"
    ],
    answer: "End-User Development"
  },
  {
    question: "EUC stands for:",
    options: [
      "End-User Computing",
      "End-User Collaboration",
      "End-User Configuration",
      "End-User Communication"
    ],
    answer: "End-User Computing"
  },
  {
    question: "What is an Electronic Communications System?",
    options: [
      "A system that enables slow and costly communication channels.",
      "An information system that facilitates communication using telegraphy only.",
      "A type of system that provides fast and inexpensive communication channels using available resources such as telephony, computing hardware, networks, and the Internet.",
      "A system that restricts communication to handwritten letters only."
    ],
    answer: "A type of system that provides fast and inexpensive communication channels using available resources such as telephony, computing hardware, networks, and the Internet."
  },
  {
    question: "Which type of electronic communication system requires members to be available at the same time to communicate?",
    options: [
      "Synchronous ",
      "Asynchronous",
      "Instantaneous",
      "Real-time"
    ],
    answer: "Synchronous "
  },
  {
    question: "Which type of electronic communication system does not require members to be available at the same time to communicate?",
    options: [
      "Synchronous",
      "Asynchronous ",
      "Instantaneous",
      "Real-time"
    ],
    answer: "Asynchronous "
  },
  {
    question: "What is Electronic Conferencing?",
    options: [
      "A primarily asynchronous component of an electronic communication system.",
      "A method of communication that restricts collaboration between organization/business members.",
      "A mostly synchronous component of an electronic communication system encouraging greater collaboration between organization/business members. ",
      "A physical location where electronic devices are used for communication purposes."
    ],
    answer: "A mostly synchronous component of an electronic communication system encouraging greater collaboration between organization/business members. "
  },
  {
    question: "Which type of Electronic Conferencing involves only two points, allowing communication between two members?",
    options: [
      "Unipoint",
      "Singlepoint",
      "Point-to-Point ",
      "Solo Conferencing"
    ],
    answer: "Point-to-Point "
  },
  {
    question: "In which type of Electronic Conferencing do multiple members communicate simultaneously through a central network hub?",
    options: [
      "Multicast",
      "Multipoint ",
      "Omni Conferencing",
      "Broadcast"
    ],
    answer: "Multipoint "
  },
  {
    question: "What is an Electronic Meeting System (EMS)?",
    options: [
      "A system designed solely for asynchronous communication within an organization.",
      "A tool for organizing and facilitating meetings, which can be either synchronous or asynchronous, and encompasses various support tasks. ",
      "A system primarily focused on scheduling appointments and events.",
      "A system that exclusively deals with file sharing among team members."
    ],
    answer: "A tool for organizing and facilitating meetings, which can be either synchronous or asynchronous, and encompasses various support tasks. "
  },
  {
    question: "What is Electronic Discussion?",
    options: [
      "An information system primarily used for file sharing among members.",
      "A system solely dedicated to scheduling meetings and appointments electronically.",
      "An electronic medium utilized for facilitating textual or non-textual discussions among members. ",
      "A tool exclusively for real-time audio/video communication within an organization."
    ],
    answer: "An electronic medium utilized for facilitating textual or non-textual discussions among members. "
  },
  {
    question: "Which type of Electronic Discussion technology requires users to actively access the discussion by initiating a specific action?",
    options: [
      "Push Technologies",
      "Active Technologies",
      "Pull Technologies ",
      "Accessible Technologies"
    ],
    answer: "Pull Technologies "
  },
  {
    question: "In which type of Electronic Discussion technology does the discussion content come to the user without the need for any action from their end?",
    options: [
      "Active Technologies",
      "Push Technologies ",
      "Engage Technologies",
      "Involve Technologies"
    ],
    answer: "Push Technologies "
  },
  {
    question: "What is Electronic Publishing?",
    options: [
      "The process of printing physical copies of textual material using electronic devices.",
      "The digital publication of textual material and other readable information accessible through electronic devices. ",
      "A system exclusively designed for sharing audio content online.",
      "The distribution of printed materials through electronic mail."
    ],
    answer: "The digital publication of textual material and other readable information accessible through electronic devices. "
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following examples of Electronic Publishing involves the distribution of digital copies that mimic traditional paper-based media?",
    options: [
      "Portable Electronic Media",
      "Electronic Versions of Traditional Media ",
      "New Media",
      "Online Collaboration and Sharing"
    ],
    answer: "Electronic Versions of Traditional Media "
  },
  {
    question: "Which example of Electronic Publishing relies solely on the Internet for dissemination and interaction with target audiences?",
    options: [
      "Portable Electronic Media",
      "Electronic Versions of Traditional Media",
      "New Media ",
      "Online Collaboration and Sharing"
    ],
    answer: "New Media "
  },
  {
    question: "Which example of Electronic Publishing uses physical means of storing and publishing electronic textual content, such as CDs/DVDs/BDs, Flash Drives, or External Hard Drives?",
    options: [
      "Portable Electronic Media ",
      "Electronic Versions of Traditional Media",
      "New Media",
      "Online Collaboration and Sharing"
    ],
    answer: "Portable Electronic Media "
  },
  {
    question: "Which example of Electronic Publishing also uses Internet connectivity to facilitate publishing, but with particular emphasis on collaboration between recipients, such as Podcasts, Collaborative Software, and Cloud Sharing?",
    options: [
      "Portable Electronic Media",
      "Electronic Versions of Traditional Media",
      "New Media",
      "Online Collaboration and Sharing "
    ],
    answer: "Online Collaboration and Sharing "
  },
  {
    question: "What is one of the primary environmental benefits of electronic publishing?",
    options: [
      "Increased paper consumption",
      "Reduced need for physical storage space ",
      "Higher carbon footprint compared to traditional publishing",
      "Dependence on non-renewable resources"
    ],
    answer: "Reduced need for physical storage space "
  },
  {
    question: "How does electronic publishing facilitate quick distribution of content?",
    options: [
      "By requiring physical shipping of materials",
      "Through the use of traditional printing presses",
      "Via the Internet and digital platforms ",
      "By limiting access to a select few recipients"
    ],
    answer: "Via the Internet and digital platforms "
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following business models can be facilitated by electronic publishing?",
    options: [
      "Brick-and-mortar bookstores",
      "Door-to-door newspaper delivery",
      "Online advertising ",
      "Handwritten manuscripts"
    ],
    answer: "Online advertising "
  },
  {
    question: "What makes electronically published material easily portable?",
    options: [
      "Its large physical size",
      "Inability to be accessed without a printer",
      "Accessibility via flash drives and digital devices ",
      "Heavy reliance on physical libraries"
    ],
    answer: "Accessibility via flash drives and digital devices "
  },
  {
    question: "What is a potential risk associated with security in electronic publishing?",
    options: [
      "Physical damage to printed materials",
      "Exposure to natural disasters",
      "Data piracy",
      "Copyright infringement"
    ],
    answer: "Data piracy"
  },
  {
    question: "How can organizations address the risk of plagiarism in electronic publishing?",
    options: [
      "Implementing traditional printing methods",
      "Using digital watermarks",
      "Restricting access to published content",
      "Encrypting all electronic documents"
    ],
    answer: "Using digital watermarks"
  },
  {
    question: "What potential challenge arises concerning public perception and business models in electronic publishing?",
    options: [
      "Limited access to published content",
      "Difficulty in maintaining digital archives",
      "Resistance to online subscription models",
      "Increased cost of physical distribution"
    ],
    answer: "Resistance to online subscription models"
  },
  {
    question: "Which risk of electronic publishing involves potential disagreement with prevailing attitudes toward online content?",
    options: [
      "Security Issues",
      "Plagiarism",
      "Public Opinion on Business Models",
      "Environmental Impact"
    ],
    answer: "Public Opinion on Business Models"
  },
    {
    question: "What term describes communication within an organization where information flows from managers and superiors down through different departments?",
    options: [
      "Internal, Downward",
      "Internal, Upward",
      "Internal, Lateral",
      "External"
    ],
    answer: "Internal, Downward"
  },
  {
    question: "Which term refers to communication within an organization where subordinates send information upwards to their superiors?",
    options: [
      "Internal, Downward",
      "Internal, Upward",
      "Internal, Lateral",
      "External"
    ],
    answer: "Internal, Upward"
  },
  {
    question: "What term encompasses communication between co-workers or co-members, including cross-department communication?",
    options: [
      "Internal, Downward",
      "Internal, Upward",
      "Internal, Lateral",
      "External"
    ],
    answer: "Internal, Lateral"
  },
  {
    question: "Which term describes communication that involves external parties such as customers, prospects, vendors, or partners?",
    options: [
      "Internal, Downward",
      "Internal, Upward",
      "Internal, Lateral",
      "External"
    ],
    answer: "External"
  },
  {
    question: "What term describes the communication connectivity of a business or organization to its various aspects, including prospective clients, branches, and departments, in order to streamline specific processes or tasks?",
    options: [
      "Data Mining",
      "Networking",
      "Cloud Computing",
      "Data Encryption"
    ],
    answer: "Networking"
  },
  {
    question: "What term describes a network type where communication flows from a single member, often a managerial or executive figure, to all other members?",
    options: [
      "Chain Network",
      "Circle Network",
      "Star Network",
      "Wheel Network"
    ],
    answer: "Wheel Network"
  },
  {
    question: "What term refers to a network type where communication follows a set sequence, typically from the top-level management down to different departments and employees?",
    options: [
      "Chain Network",
      "Circle Network",
      "Star Network",
      "Wheel Network"
    ],
    answer: "Chain Network"
  },
  {
    question: "What term represents a network type characterized by communication between superiors and subordinates, with cross-communication at the operative level, often arranged in a three-level hierarchy?",
    options: [
      "Chain Network",
      "Circle Network",
      "Star Network",
      "Wheel Network"
    ],
    answer: "Circle Network"
  },
  {
    question: "What term describes a network type where each member can communicate with all other members, allowing for high participation and collaboration without designated communication pathways?",
    options: [
      "Chain Network",
      "Circle Network",
      "Star Network",
      "Wheel Network"
    ],
    answer: "Star Network"
  },
  {
    question: "What term defines the organizational system within an enterprise that utilizes electronically-controlled technologies and resources to enhance the efficiency of business activities, encompassing functions from selling products and services to customer support?",
    options: [
      "E-Commerce",
      "E-Business",
      "Digital Marketing",
      "Online Retail"
    ],
    answer: "E-Business"
  },
  {
    question: "What does e-business facilitate in terms of Operation Cost Reduction?",
    options: [
      "Increase in manual labor expenses",
      "Reduction in telecommunication charges",
      "Rise in traditional communication costs",
      "Expansion of physical infrastructure costs"
    ],
    answer: "Reduction in telecommunication charges"
  },
  {
    question: "How does e-business enhance customer service efficiency?",
    options: [
      "By decreasing reach and reliability",
      "By slowing down service delivery",
      "By improving reach, speed, and reliability",
      "By increasing manual processes"
    ],
    answer: "By improving reach, speed, and reliability"
  },
  {
    question: "What advantage does e-business provide in terms of wider market access?",
    options: [
      "Narrowing the target market reach",
      "Limiting marketing strategies to specific locations",
      "Enabling access to a broader target market",
      "Restricting international outreach"
    ],
    answer: "Enabling access to a broader target market"
  },
  {
    question: "What is a primary application of e-business solutions involving websites?",
    options: [
      "Customer-Centered Retailing",
      "Internet Business Models",
      "E-Commerce Support Systems",
      "Traditional Retailing"
    ],
    answer: "Internet Business Models"
  },
  {
    question: "How do companies utilize e-business solutions for customer-centered retailing?",
    options: [
      "By incorporating reviews from websites and review services",
      "By limiting access to product information",
      "By avoiding online commerce",
      "By ignoring consumer feedback"
    ],
    answer: "By incorporating reviews from websites and review services"
  },
  {
    question: "What type of services can companies offer through e-commerce support systems?",
    options: [
      "Product development",
      "Credit-card transaction processing/e-payment systems",
      "Physical distribution of products",
      "Traditional advertising campaigns"
    ],
    answer: "Credit-card transaction processing/e-payment systems"
  },
  {
    question: "What term describes a computerized system designed to record, process, validate, and store transactions occurring within various functional areas of a business for future retrieval and use?",
    options: [
      "Transactional Database",
      "Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP)",
      "Decision Support System (DSS)",
      "Transaction Processing System (TPS)"
    ],
    answer: "Transaction Processing System (TPS)"
  },
  {
    question: "What type of transaction occurs within a company and is related to its internal processes?",
    options: [
      "Internal",
      "External",
      "Interdepartmental",
      "Cross-functional"
    ],
    answer: "Internal"
  },
  {
    question: "Which type of transaction is external to any organization and involves interactions with external sources?",
    options: [
      "Internal",
      "External",
      "Interdepartmental",
      "Cross-functional"
    ],
    answer: "External"
  },
  {
    question: "Based on the provided characteristics, what is a Transaction Processing System (TPS)?",
    options: [
      "A system that records internal and external transactions, accessed by other systems.",
      "A system primarily used by lower-level managers for operational decisions.",
      "A system capable of recording transactions in batch mode or online.",
      "A system that performs six main steps in processing a transaction."
    ],
    answer: "A system that records internal and external transactions, accessed by other systems."
  },
  {
    question: "What process involves capturing transaction data as close to the source as possible in a Transaction Processing System (TPS)?",
    options: [
      "Data Entry",
      "Data Validation",
      "Data Capture",
      "Data Processing and Revalidation"
    ],
    answer: "Data Capture"
  },
  {
    question: "Which step in a TPS focuses on detecting and correcting errors in transaction data?",
    options: [
      "Data Entry",
      "Data Capture",
      "Data Validation",
      "Data Processing and Revalidation"
    ],
    answer: "Data Validation"
  },
  {
    question: "What is the initial step in the process of a Transaction Processing System (TPS) where transaction data is entered into the system for processing, often using input devices such as the keyboard and mouse?",
    options: [
      "Data Validation",
      "Data Processing",
      "Data Entry",
      "Data Output"
    ],
    answer: "Data Entry"
  },
  {
    question: "What step in the Transaction Processing System (TPS) involves processing transactions, which can occur either online with almost instantaneous processing or in batch mode where transactions are accumulated over time?",
    options: [
      "Data Validation",
      "Data Entry",
      "Data Processing and Revalidation",
      "Data Output"
    ],
    answer: "Data Processing and Revalidation"
  },
  {
    question: "What step in the Transaction Processing System (TPS) involves storing processed data for future use, considering factors such as the type of processing and the storage medium's capacity?",
    options: [
      "Data Validation",
      "Data Entry",
      "Data Processing and Revalidation",
      "Data Storage"
    ],
    answer: "Data Storage"
  },
  {
    question: "What feature of the Transaction Processing System (TPS) allows users to access and process previously stored data by providing specific parameters for data retrieval?",
    options: [
      "Data Validation",
      "Data Entry",
      "Output Generation",
      "Query Support"
    ],
    answer: "Query Support"
  },
  {
    question: "What step in the Transaction Processing System (TPS) involves communicating processed data to decision-makers and relevant parties through documents/reports (physical copies) or forms (digital, soft copies)?",
    options: [
      "Data Validation",
      "Data Entry",
      "Query Support",
      "Output Generation"
    ],
    answer: "Output Generation"
  },
  {
    question: "What term describes a type of information system capable of recording, processing, and reporting routine and repetitive activities across various departments within an organization?",
    options: [
      "Operational Information System (OIS)",
      "End-User Computing (EUC)",
      "End User Development (EUD)",
      "Management Information System (MIS)"
    ],
    answer: "Operational Information System (OIS)"
  },
  {
    question: "What term describes the capability of an operational information system to streamline processes, particularly those involving manual labor, thereby reducing operational costs?",
    options: [
      "Increased Speed",
      "Increased Accuracy",
      "Reduced Cost",
      "Increased Customer Service"
    ],
    answer: "Reduced Cost"
  },
  {
    question: "What term refers to the ability of an operational information system to expedite routine processes by leveraging its processing power?",
    options: [
      "Increased Speed",
      "Increased Accuracy",
      "Reduced Cost",
      "Increased Customer Service"
    ],
    answer: "Increased Speed"
  },
  {
    question: "Which term characterizes the feature of an operational information system that minimizes or eliminates human errors by employing a reliable process algorithm?",
    options: [
      "Increased Speed",
      "Increased Accuracy",
      "Reduced Cost",
      "Increased Customer Service"
    ],
    answer: "Increased Accuracy"
  },
  {
    question: "What term represents the capability of an operational information system to optimize customer service processes, ensuring efficient delivery?",
    options: [
      "Increased Speed",
      "Increased Accuracy",
      "Reduced Cost",
      "Increased Customer Service"
    ],
    answer: "Increased Customer Service"
  },
  {
    question: "What term describes the function of an operational information system to store and generate relevant data for reports, documents, and forms, facilitating decision-making by managers and executives?",
    options: [
      "Increased Speed",
      "Increased Accuracy",
      "Data Streamlining",
      "Increased Data for Decision Making"
    ],
    answer: "Increased Data for Decision Making"
  }
];


export default MIS;
